Oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh
EUR的に ever bij filmer
zoid your life
Road to crime
ほな夢の一輪
いつか焼煙ようと
もう自由は志もう
CREDI watching
Music
texted
Thank you.
Goodness.
What news is it that concerns you today, brother?
You look rather serious.
Tua, it's nothing of any great import.
A widely known and well-loved painting
was the subject of vandalism late last night in the spa town of Bath.
The defaced work featuring several white lilies
was originally painted by philanthropist and local celebrity Baron Cubitt,
though the culprit and his motive currently remain unknown.
Is it the nobility of the artist that raises your suspicions?
Not exactly.
I don't know much about this particular nobleman.
It's the ruined painting.
There's something devilishly familiar about it.
It's weird.
It looks like one I saw in the slums long ago.
In the days before that wretched orphanage, I imagine.
Well, if it concerns you, investigate.
I'd like to, but...
Oh, go have a log.
The others ought to be returning from their mission soon.
And I have my own work to attend to.
Very well then.
Thank you.
We're in the right place.
This is where the defaced painting was originally displayed.
The surrounding works were also painted by Baron Cubitt.
Well, there's no doubt.
He's the same artist responsible for the one I remember from the slums.
Hmm.
So do you imagine our vandal has some connection to the illustrious Lord Cubitt?
His carriage just arrived.
He says he'd like to look around the gallery first.
Very well then.
Luke, I hate to ask, but would you deliver this?
Certainly, sir.
The boy seems awfully hurried.
I wanted to see you.
He's the same artist responsible for the one I remember from the slums.
Hmm.
So do you imagine our vandal has some connection to the illustrious Lord Cubitt?
His carriage just arrived.
He says he'd like to look around the gallery first.
Very well, then.
Luke, I hate to ask, but would you deliver this?
Certainly, sir.
The boy seems awfully hurried.
I wonder if his errand has to do with our case.
Do you think perhaps we ought to follow him?
No, we're on no pressing schedule.
I have a better idea in mind.
It's been a long time since we could relax together like this, hasn't it?
It has.
It reminds me of our time with Lord Rockwell.
That's the last I can remember bathing together.
But what should we do after this?
What indeed?
I'd like to meet with the painter as soon as possible.
There's something I would like to ask him.
All right, then.
I'll send a message to Lord Cupid once we leave.
Stanley.
Hmm?
The painter I encountered in the slums all those years ago
was a Mr. Stanley, not a Lord Cupid.
What?
Hey!
Liam, look up!
Fancy seeing you here!
Ugh.
Sherlock Holmes.
That's Sherlock Holmes, the famous detective from London.
He must be here!
It's been too long, Mr. Holmes.
I'm delighted to see you both looking so well.
Yes, the same to you, sir.
And thank you again for all your assistance on the train.
Oh, please think nothing of it.
It was Mr. Holmes who solved the case in the end.
Ha, balderdash.
But I'm more interested in the here and now, Liam.
Why Bath?
Merely sightseeing, I'm afraid.
I thought a visit to the hot springs was in order.
Though it appears you, sir, are here on some manner of business.
Yes, well.
I'm here on behalf of Baron Cupid and his artistic endeavours.
I am Jean-Paul Marais, art dealer.
So you're here about the vandalism?
It was in the papers.
Oh, good, you know of it.
I'm sorry to say, the local police have been of no use in this affair.
Which is why I thought I might enlist the help of the greatest detective in all London,
Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
Of course, I'm more than happy to pay for whatever services you may provide.
I've set aside three hundred pounds.
Three hundred pounds?
That would cover the cost of repairs from the time we blew up the flat.
And Miss Hudson might find it in her heart to get off our backs.
The whole affair did sound quite intriguing.
Oh, we should be off.
It's almost time for our appointment with Baron Cupid.
Ah, so it is.
An appointment with the Baron, you say?
Indeed.
I thought, why not see the painting with my own eyes?
If it's not an imposition, Lewis and I would love to join you.
Mr. Holmes, Dr. Watson, it's a pleasure.
Murray has told me all about you.
I, of course, am Baron Cupid.
But who are these gentlemen?
These are my friends, the brothers Moriarty, William in the top hat and Lewis in the bowler.
I bumped into them in town.
They would also like to see your painting.
I trust that won't be a problem.
Pleasure to meet you, Lord Cupid.
William James Moriarty at your service.
I hope you'll forgive our dropping by uninvited.
Oh, please.
It's no trouble at all, Lord Moriarty.
This is appalling.
I hope you'll pardon me for asking, but how much do your paintings usually sell for?
It depends on the piece.
But they often command in the range of 500 pounds.
500?
Then perhaps the culprit is simply displeased with your work being so profitable.
If they know what they're worth, then they should know I donate the proceeds in full to local charities.
I receive no profit from my work.
Sir, I'm curious whether you might be willing to show us around your atelier.
What for?
Is this an inopportune time?
No, it's not a bother.
It's just a bit of a track away, but if you gentlemen will follow me...
My, you certainly keep it tidy in here.
Yes, I find it difficult to concentrate when things are cluttered.
This is unusual.
What is?
This pigment includes lead as one of its components.
You hardly ever see this sort of thing nowadays.
I know it's rare, but to me, no other paint is suitable for white lilies.
Besides, nothing beats painting with what you're accustomed to.
I see.
So this is the secret to the beauty of your work.
Yes.
My sketchbook.
That's odd.
I was quite sure I put that away.
The failings by which I'm quite embarrassed, forgive me.
And to be perfectly frank with you, I've had a devil of a time concentrating on anything ever since the incident occurred.
Yes, I'd imagine, sir.
I'm terribly sorry.
I shouldn't have insisted we come.
On the contrary, I'm grateful to you for asking.
But I do think it's time we return to the house.
Yes, very well.
So, did you notice anything, Sherlock?
Let's see.
Based on my initial observations, I believe that our culprit is left-handed and quite short.
How do you figure that?
Our defaced painting suffered little damage to the upper half.
The lower half bore the brunt of the assault.
But based on its position in the gallery, it's likely our vandal had to use a stepladder to reach it.
I also noticed several fine lines tracked through the paint underneath the highest brushstrokes, indicating that as they stretched out their arm, their sleeve, or possibly a lapel, rubbed against the canvas.
But what I can't tell is what drove them to do it.
Liam, why did you prompt Lord Cubitt to shake your hand?
I simply wish to follow proper etiquette, as it was my first time to meet the gentleman.
Ha.
Funny.
That's not at all what it looked like to me.
Cubitt's hands showed no signs of the man being an expert artist.
No calluses, no pigments, staining his cuticles.
In other words, that man simply does not paint.
What?
Assuming that's what the handshake was meant to discover, I think you know much more than you've let on.
My goodness.
You think far too highly of my skills.
I'm merely a long-time fan of Lord Cubitt's work.
However, I do know that you are hiding something, Mr. Holmes.
Hmm?
Are you not?
Tucked away in your pocket.
You caught that, did you?
I'm impressed.
I discovered this inside his sketchbook.
A series of numbers stained with the same paint the culprit used, which means it's very likely a message.
John and I are going to work on the meaning of this note.
What about you two?
I think Louis and I will enjoy a nice stroll as we make our way back to the hotel.
Right.
You did come here to see the sights, after all.
Then I suppose this is goodbye once again.
Indeed.
Till next time.
Louis.
I apologize for dragging you along whilst I indulged myself.
Oh, please.
Don't give it another thought.
Though I did notice something rather odd.
When we met Lord Cubitt, he had no reaction at all.
Which would indicate...
Correct.
That is not the man I met in the slums.
Louis.
Hmm?
If you will, I have a favor to ask you.
Little man.
No time.
You are not about your back.
Okay.
No time.
All minds.
Let's go.
First time.
Your turn.
Evil.
Yo.
If you will, you will hear me.
That am救.
I will hear you.
Yes.
Thank you.
My lord, a letter has arrived for you.
Ah, much obliged.
It's Cubit.
I received your letter.
I don't need to know who you are,
but please tell me how you know...
What on earth are you doing here?
I could ask the same.
What is a child doing in my atelier?
I want to talk to you.
I'll meet you at his atelier tonight.
From Stanley's friend.
I received the exact same letter.
Do you know Alan?
Uh, Mr. Stanley?
I used to be a fan of your paintings, you know that?
When there were deliveries for you,
I took them as often as I could.
So one day when I saw someone walking from your house into the woods,
I was sure it must have been you.
So I followed after them.
But then...
That was when I became friends with Mr. Stanley.
And I know that you tricked him.
Don't think you can hide what you did any longer.
Once you got your money in vain,
you didn't need Mr. Stanley anymore.
Stop this.
You don't know what you're saying.
He was...
I really didn't want to ruin that painting.
But I thought at least you wouldn't be able to use that one
to make your filthy fortune.
And now I'll see that you wait once and for all!
What?
Good sir.
You needn't stain your hands with blood at your age.
Why, Lord Moriarty?
You already have stains enough.
When I saw you in the gallery yesterday,
I admit I was baffled as to why your left sleeve
was so much shorter than the right.
But once I saw the painting,
it all made perfect sense.
Get off!
What do you want with me?
I was the one who sent those letters to you.
You were?
Then that means...
You're Mr. Stanley's friend.
Unfortunately,
Mr. Alan Stanley has passed away.
But you should know,
his death was not Lord Qubit's fault.
What?
Liam is correct.
Mr. Holmes.
My friend,
you could have been less cryptic.
The cause of this Stanley chap's death
was illness.
Wasn't it, Lord Qubit?
Yes, indeed it was.
I'm afraid he was eventually done in by Saturnism.
By what?
Lead poisoning.
From the pigments he used to mix his paint.
As the illness enters its final stages,
one sees symptoms that include intellectual decline,
irritability,
and hand tremors.
Which naturally explains why the pictures in his sketchbook
grew increasingly worse over time.
The only way to treat him
was to stop the exposure.
But he refused.
He chose to keep painting until the very end,
despite his symptoms.
If only I had tried harder,
forced him to rest,
perhaps my dear friend
would not have had to suffer the way he did.
You were truly friends?
We were.
He was the son of the stable hand
at the villa we had in London
when I was a child.
We were roughly the same age,
but my parents told me
I was not to interact with commoners.
So, for many years,
we barely spoke.
But one day,
I just happened to see
one of his paintings.
I fell in love with his work.
And that brought us together.
You know, George,
it's a bit sad,
but sometimes I wish there was a place
where even the poor could seek an education,
regardless of money or status.
But I know that dream is still an age away.
No, it isn't.
Listen, Alan,
you and your paintings have value.
You can make that happen in your lifetime.
I know it.
However,
the years slipped by
and he never sold a single painting.
Why don't we say
you're the one who painted my pieces?
Why on earth?
My work won't sell
because a commoner's name
is attached to it all.
I don't need fame.
I only need you to promise me one thing.
Use their earnings to help the poor.
And I'll be your ghost painter
for as long as you wish.
I swear it.
What do you say?
Alan, I...
And so we relocated our base of operations
to my hometown of Bath
where we sold his paintings under my name.
But it still doesn't add up.
You haven't explained those numbers.
So go on.
Make it make sense.
Numbers?
He's referring to this.
It compares the final sale
of several recent paintings
with the amount set aside
for donations to charity.
Despite the claim
that you donate all the proceeds
from your sales,
the truth is
you've only ever contributed
a few percent.
And the reason you found out
about the difference
is likely
that you've been peeking
at the letters
being sent from Cubitt Manor.
I know that what I did
was wrong, of course.
But I thought maybe I could find out
what happened to Mr. Stanley.
And then I discovered
a donation check.
So I asked your art dealer
and the aristocrats at the spa
about the price of your paintings.
And I found out
the amounts were completely different.
So then...
Indeed.
You and Mr. Stanley
were being fed false sale prices
from the beginning.
The man behind it all
is your art dealer.
He's made a small fortune off of you
simply from pocketing the difference.
And it seems he's had a hand
in other dark dealings.
as well.
Hold it, Vlad!
Get back!
How?
How does this not upset you?
If you truly knew Stanley,
then you should understand
this isn't the sort of thing
he would have wanted.
The path of vengeance
is a misery
you needn't suffer,
my friend.
This is the finish thing.
Is that the question?
Blimey, you policemen really are good for absolutely nothing, aren't you?
So what if my reported sale prices were incorrect?
We all make mistakes, don't we?
I'll sue you for wrongful arrest.
Jean-Paul Marais.
Sorry to interrupt, but we're here to take you in on suspicion of treason.
For what?
This man has been using his position as an art dealer as a cover.
He is an arms dealer for nations hostile to the crown.
Naturally, you have the right to silence.
I suggest that you use it.
You know, a friendship between a philanthropic nobleman and a destitute artist is rather heartwarming.
Though tell me, Liam, why is it that you seem to actually know this Alan Stanley chap yourself?
They're beautiful.
Flowers blooming in the gutter.
I like it.
Thank you.
My greatest hope for these works is that their purity can inspire change in people.
If these lilies can drive even one man to kindness, then I'm quite positive.
That will change the entire world.
Does that sound odd?
No.
I happen to agree.
I did know of him.
Unfortunately, I can't claim to have truly known the gentleman.
Oh.
Well, I suppose I'll leave it at that, then.
Let's go, 2, 3, 1, 2, 2...